DENYS LITVINSKYI

SENIOR IOS ENGINEER

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Ukraine

PHONE

+380500565796

EMAIL

litvinskyi.dev@gmail.com

LINKS

LinkedIn

GitHub

SKILLS

Swift

.

SwiftUI

• • • • •

Objective-C

• • • •

iOS Development

• • • • •

Xcode

• • • • •

JavaScript

 \bullet \bullet \circ \circ

Rust

• • 0 0 0

LANGUAGES

Ukraine

• • • •

English

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

PROFILE

A Mobile Developer with experience in analysis, design, development, implementation, and testing. Specialize in developing applications for the iOS platform with rich and intuitive GUI. Solid background in computer science and practical programming skills. a self-motivated, quick learner, and a good team player.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior iOS Software Engineer, Dispo Inc.

Los Angeles(Remote)

Jan 2022 — Jan 2023

- Develop a photo&video application for a startup company based in Los Angeles
- · Build architecture for core features
- · Write and support Unit tests
- · Collaboration with the design team to provide the best UX
- Collaboration with the VP of Engineering and back-end team to develop new API for iOS features

Swift, SwiftUI, Combine, TCA, MVVM, AVFoundation, Metal, GRDB, Realm

Senior/Lead iOS Software Engineer, InnerCircle

Amsterdam(Remote)

Dec 2019 — Dec 2022

- · Lead a development team to build a dating application
- · Refactor legacy code
- · Build a new architecture for an application feature
- · Introduce new technologies to keep product up-to-date
- · Write and support Unit tests
- · Setup and maintain CI/CD server
- Collaborate with the Head of Engineering to create a roadmap for new releases
- · Collaborate with the back-end team to develop API for new features
- · Collaborate with the QA team to keep the best quality of the product

Swift, Objective-C, UIKit, SwiftUI, Combine, MVVM, Realm, CoreML, Vision

iOS Software Engineer, SprinkleGroup

Dnipro(Remote)

Jun 2018 — Dec 2019

- · Develop stock trading applications
- Refactor legacy code
- · Take a part in building core SDK
- Collaborate with CEO and Product Owner to collect requirements, estimate, and plan features
- Create CI/CD server
- · Remove unnecessary 3rd party dependencies and build native modules

Swift, Objective-C, UIKit, RxSwift, ReactiveKit, MVP, CoreData, Realm

iOS Software Engineer, Bonosoft

Dnipro

Oct 2017 — May 2018

- · Develop an audio&video messenger application
- · Refactor legacy code
- · Write and support Unit tests
- · Collaborate with the CEO to plan and estimate features

Swift, Objective-C, UIKit, RxSwift, MVP, CoreData, Realm, WebRTC, AVFoundation

iOS Software Engineer, «LionsShare» App3Null GmbH

Kyiv

Feb 2017 — Aug 2017

- · Work as outsource and out staff engineer
- Develop multiple iOS applications: speech recognition, social application, game, and health&fitness app

Swift, Objective-C, UIKit, AVFoundation, text-to-speech

iOS Software Engineer, Spire LLC

Kyiv

May 2014 — Jan 2017

- · Work as outsource and out staff developer
- Develop multiple iOS applications: games, keyboard extensions, social apps, FinTech apps, photo&video app

Objective-C, Swift, AFNetworking/Alamofire, CoreLocation, CoreData

EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Computer Science, Zaporizhzhia Institute of Economics and Information Technologies

Zaporizhzhia

2012 — 2015

Master's of Computer Science, Zaporizhzhia Institute of Economics and Information Technologies

Zaporizhzhia

2015 - 2018